# GERRIT BOND

ENGINEERING MANAGER



### CONTACT

+1 804 305 0132

Baltimore, MD

侧 @gerrit-bond

## EDUCATION

#### **BACHELOR'S DEGREE**

Computer Science

Virginia Commonwealth University 2015

## SKILLS

- Project Management
- Mentorship
- System Design + Architecture
- Distributed Systems
- C#
- Python
- NodeJS
- Java
- Containers
- Terraform
- AWS Proficiency
- SQL
- Redis
- DynamoDB
- Kafka
- RabbitMQ

# SUMMARY

I'm a skilled Engineering Manager who builds and motivates high-performing software engineering teams. I have over nine years of experience working on complex projects across product boundaries and across company sizes. My throughline is a focus on rapid and efficient delivery of value for the project, and the overall business.

I find the most rewarding part of my job to be growing and enabling a capable, well-motivated engineering team thereby improving an organization's ability to deliver.

## EXPERIENCE

### **Engineering Manager**

Tomorrow Health / New York (Remote) / June 2023 - Present

- Led two engineering teams simultaneously, one a product-aligned team focused on improving complex core systems; the other a DevOps squad improving our infrastructure.
- Hired 4 Senior FTEs (DevOps, Backend), and 1 Junior FTE from operations through internal mentoring on the team. Promoted 1 FTE to a Staff level. Maintained 93% anonymous manager satisfaction as a management team vs. ~70% company wide.
- Launched Fax Automation, a capability which enabled device suppliers to save 30+% of their time when processing faxed medical documentation.
- Expanded benefits of Fax Automation, with regular Product partnership to provide internal work-time reduction; brought enhanced visibility to referring practices for fax based orders.
- Oversaw and reduced overall infrastructure spending by 10% through right-sizing of our resources and adjusting retention policies.
- Designed, and led implementation of SMS consent tracking in line with regulations such as TCPA. Consulted with legal representation to enable the business, white mitigating potential legal risk.

# **Engineering Manager**

Imperfect Foods / Misfits Market / California (Remote) / June 2022 – April 2023

- Led the team to identify and remediate significant technical debt, reducing after-hours incident frequency from 2 per week, to 1 per month.
- Led the integration between operations systems between Misfits Market and Imperfect Foods as part of the acquisition. I designed and led the implementation of core data syncing between the systems ahead of the organization being fully involved.
- Led the team to integrate a warehouse management system in 5 operations centers across the country. Collaborated closely with operations, and other cross-functional stakeholders to identify requirements and assess issues rapidly.
- Hired 2 Senior FTEs (Backend), handling hiring, onboarding, training, and growth in the organization.

# INTERESTS

**Tabletop Gaming** 

Traveling

Baking

Teaching

## Senior Software Engineer

Imperfect Foods / California (Remote) / May 2021– June 2022

- Implemented an inventory management system, responsible for facilitating receiving, packing, and recounting activities within the warehouse. Integrated inventory counts with our accounting system.
- Worked with the team to evaluate our existing microservices, and review
  the boundaries between them. Established new bounded contexts
  following event storming exercises and team review.
- Worked with the team to integrate Kafka as a message queue for the larger system architecture.
- Developed and supported multiple in-house tools enabling operations to correctly pack and ship thousands of boxes per day.

## Senior Software Engineer

Capital One, Commercial Bank / Richmond, VA / June 2019 - May 2021

- Developed a covenant management system, as part of a legacy platform migration.
- Developed a proof-of-concept event sourced solution for measuring compliance on a loan's covenants.
- Assisted in delivery of time-sensitive applications such as a modernized pricing model and a legislatively required exceptions framework.

#### Senior Consultant

UDig Consulting / Richmond, VA / August 2016 – June 2019

- Developed an event management system for a national union. Responsible for event registration, reporting, and vote allocation to union affiliates as part of their regular elections.
- Began UDig's investment in a data science offering. Worked on developing a customer acquisition model for an insurance company, and a member risk model for a major motor club.
- Created and managed an internal knowledge sharing program, responsible for organizing a regular series of talks from the broader team spanning problems across technologies and clients.
- Formalized, managed, and mentored UDig's consultant internship program.